Arif Gunawan

Boiler Field Operator

Jl. Garuda No.66 Landasan Ulin Timur, Kota Banjar Baru, Kalimantan selatan | 082123624207 | Arzgun1@gmail.com |

SUMMARY

My name is Arif Gunawan From Kalimantan. I have experience as Boiler Operator for 5 years on Coal Fired Powerplant 2x100 MW, I also understand about compressor system (oil free & oil inject), ash handling system, fuel oil system & ESP

EXPERIENCE

PT SKS Listrik Kalimantan 2 X 100MW

Boiler Operator Field (Januari 2021 - Now)

- Make Sure All Equipment and Area Boiler, ESP, Compressor and Ash Handling is safe and clean
- Routin Inspection area of All fans, Coal feeder, ESP, Compressor, Aux boiler and Ash handling
- Make Daily Logsheet of All Fans, Coal feeder and Compressor
- Make Daily report Routin Inspection Field Area
- Check and try to resolve abnormal condition the equipment
- Report Equipment Failures to the Foreman

•

PT SKS Listrik Kalimantan 2 X 100MW

Field Operator Boiler (5 Mei 2019 - Desember 2019)

- Join Commissioning Team Project of IPP Kalteng-1:
- Check the completeness of Equipment P&ID and KKS Code in Boiler, ESP, Compressor & Ash Handling System
- Doing witness the loop test, Solo Run Test, Mechanical Test, and Interlock Test, every equipment referring documents Request For Inspection (RFI) Documents
- Make sure All Area Boiler Compressor and ash handling stay safe and clean
- Followed and learn Operator Field From Dongfang

•

PT DSS Karawang 1

Plant Operator (2018 - 2019)

- Learning Diagram flow of Power Plant
- Learn and Operate the equipment Boiler system
- Inspection Area Field All fans, Coal feeder, ESP and Compressor
- Make Daily Logsheet of All fans
- Make Daily report Coal Consumptions

PT Intraco Penta Prima Servis

Mekanik (21 januari 2016 - 23 Maret 2016)

- PKL (Praktek Kerja Lapangan)
- Joint Project Overhaul 26 Unit ADT A40G:
- Replace Tire, Oil Filter, Cleaning Engine, Replace Oil Engine, Repalce Head Piston

• Check and Cleaning Hydraulic system, Fuel System

EDUCATION

2018 - 2019

Pembangkit Tenaga Listrik D1 - Institut Teknologi PLN

Pengoperasian dan pemeliharaan PLTU

2015 - 2018

Teknik Alat Berat - SMK PGRI Banjar Baru

Mempelajari Bagian-bagian Dari Alat berat Seperti Excavator, Dump Truck, Wheel Loader dan Bulldozer

Mempelajari Tentang Sistem yang ada di Alat Berat

SKILL

- Microsoft word
- Microsoft Excel

LANGUAGE

- Indonesia
- Inggris